SCOUT BURGHARDT

CODEBAR STUDENT & ASPIRING DEVELOPER

ABOUT

I am a self-taught developer and codebar student with two years of learning. I am most proficient in backend development with Python and Ruby.

As co-founder of a housing co-operative, I am experienced in collaboration and teamwork. As a Gender Studies and European Ethnology postgraduate I have honed a wide range of transferable skills, in particular problem solving and communication.

I love technology, learning, and building and creating things, and I am looking for a career change.

CONTACT

+44 7845 737 169 scout.burghardt@gmail.com github.com/cybergrrl codewars.com/users/cybergrrl

QUALIFICATION

2011

Magistra Artium (Master of Arts) in Gender Studies and European Ethnology Humboldt University of Berlin grade 1.2 (First)

CODING

CODEBAR

- attended regularly since 2017
- · codebar and other tutorials

FLATIRON SCHOOL CODING BOOTCAMP PREP

- online course covering basics in Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- test-driven IDE pushing completed lessons to github

RUBY

- completed working through Ruby Wizardry by Eric Weinstein
- wrote text-based adventure game (see github)

PYTHON

- 25% into The Complete Python Bootcamp on Udemy
- set up and worked with Pycharm and Jupyter Notebook

WORK HISTORY

2014 TO PRESENT

Freelance translator, copy editor, and proof-reader for German and English Note taker at the University of Sussex

JUNE 2018

Database management for Real DPO, London (freelance):

- reviewing existing Access database, ensuring consistency and correctness
- liaising with support workers, managers, and database admin to ensure maximum usability

2016

Coder for Camino-Werkstatt Berlin:

- coding evaluations of human rights projects according to a set of categories and characteristics
- evaluating methods and outcomes of projects

2014

Coder for a review of evaluations of interventions commissioned by the UK Department for International Development (DFID):

- coding evaluations of interventions on violence against women and girls in (post-) conflict contexts
- review of evaluation approaches regarding methodology, quality, outcomes and methods
- Qualitative Comparative Analysis

2012-13

Customer care and data admin at United Global Trading Ltd, Brighton

- customer care (calls and emails)
- writing copy (English and German)
- uploading products to a range of websites (EBay, Amazon, and company websites using Magento)

COMMUNITY WORK & VOLUNTEERING

2011 TO PRESENT

Rosa Bridge Housing Co-operative:

- setting up the co-operative, writing policies, securing funding, purchasing property
- ongoing management of communal life
- · financial planning and accounting
- liaising with local and national cooperative networks
- training new co-ops in how to set up and in financial planning

PRE 2011

active member of the Berlin LGBTQ community:

- running club nights and setting up film screening series
- organising and participating in protests and pride events

organiser in student politics:

- Elected member and chair of the student parliament (Studierendenparlament)
- Elected member of the General Student's Committee (ReferentInnen-Rat) as head of welfare section (Sozialreferat) at Humboldt University Berlin

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

2010

Samenbanken – Samenspender. Ethnographische und historische Perspektiven auf Männlichkeiten in der Reproduktionsmedizin, Berlin (book co-edited with Dr Michi Knecht, article co-written with Kerstin Tote)

2008

Embracing Victim Status in German Memorial Debates – Identity Politics Reloaded. In: Bound and Unbound. Interdisciplinary Approaches to Genders and Sexualities, Cambridge